import { quizDataProps } from "@/types/quiz-data";

export const quantitativeAptitudeQuizData: quizDataProps[] = [
  {
    question: "Express 252 as a product of primes.",
    answers: [
      "2 * 2 * 3 * 3 * 7",
      "3* 3 * 3 * 3 * 7",
      "2 * 2 * 2* 3 * 7",
      "2 * 3 * 3 * 3 * 7",
    ],
    correct: "2 * 2 * 3 * 3 * 7",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the highest common factor of the following numbers: 4 * 27 * 3125, 8 * 9 * 25 * 7, 16 * 81 * 5 * 11 * 49",
    answers: ["180", "360", "540", "1260"],
    correct: "180",
  },
  {
    question: "Calculate the HCF of 1.08, 0.36 and 0.9.",
    answers: ["0.03", "0.9", "0.18", "0.108"],
    correct: "0.18",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Three numbers are in the ratio 1:2:3 and their HCF is 12. The numbers are:",
    answers: ["4, 8, 12", "5, 10, 15", "10, 20, 30", "12, 24, 36"],
    correct: "12, 24, 36",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The sum if two numbers is 528 and their HCF is 33. The number of pairs of numbers satisfying the above condition is:",
    answers: ["4", "6", "8", "12"],
    correct: "4",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Three friends started running together on a circular track at 8:00:00 am. Time taken by them to complete one round of the track is 15 min, 20 min, 30 min respectively. If they run continuously without any halts, then at what time will they meet again at the starting point for the fourth time?",
    answers: ["8:30:00 am", "9:00:00 pm", "12:00:00 pm", "12:00:00 am"],
    correct: "12:00:00 pm",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Two numbers are in the ratio 3 : 5. If their L.C.M. is 75, what is the sum of the numbers?",
    answers: ["25", "45", "40", "50"],
    correct: "40",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Three numbers are in the ratio of 2 : 3 : 4 and their L.C.M. is 240. Their H.C.F. is:",
    answers: ["40", "20", "30", "10"],
    correct: "20",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the least number which is exactly divisible by 6, 12, 9 and 18?",
    answers: ["96", "36", "24", "81"],
    correct: "36",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Given two numbers x and y such that 1. x^3 + y^3 = 9 2. x + y = 3. Find the value of x^4 + y^4.",
    answers: ["2/3", "7", "13", "17"],
    correct: "17",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The value of x + 1/2x is given as 2, then find the value of 8x^3 + 1/x^3.",
    answers: ["40", "32", "07", "28"],
    correct: "40",
  },
  {
    question: "Solve for x in the equation: log(2x - 1) + log(3) = log(x + 5).",
    answers: ["x = -1/3", "x = 1/3", "x = 5/3", "x = 8/5"],
    correct: "x = 8/5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the value of b^2 + 1/b^2 = 1, then find the value of b^3 + 1/b^3.",
    answers: ["-1/2", "-1", "-2", "None of the above"],
    correct: "None of the above",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Calculate the arithmetic mean of the given series: 2, 6, 10, 14, 18, 22, 26, 30.",
    answers: ["8", "16", "32", "None of the above"],
    correct: "16",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the Arithmetic mean of series: 10, 7, 4, 1, -2.",
    answers: ["13/2", "14/3", "4", "16/5"],
    correct: "4",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Calculate the sum of given series: 1/3, 1/9, 1/27, 1/81.................",
    answers: ["1/4", "1/3", "1/2", "1"],
    correct: "1/2",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a box, there are 10p, 25p and 50p coins in the ratio 4:9:5 with the total sum of Rs 206. How many coins of each kind does the box have?",
    answers: [
      "200, 360, 160",
      "135, 250, 150",
      "90, 60, 110",
      "Cannot be determined ",
    ],
    correct: "200, 360, 160",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Mark, Steve and Bill get their salaries in the ratio of 2:3:5. If their salaries are incremented by 15%, 10%, and 20% respectively, the new ratio of their salaries becomes:",
    answers: ["8:16:15", "23:33:60", "33:30:20", "21:25:32"],
    correct: "23:33:60",
  },
  {
    question: "If (x:y) = 2:1, then (x²-y²):(x²+y²) = __ ?",
    answers: ["1:2", "3:5", "2:1", "5:4"],
    correct: "3:5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the ages of Jacob, Max and Samuel are in the proportion 3:5:7 and the average of their ages is 25 years, then find the age of the youngest person.",
    answers: ["15 years", "10 years", "7 years", "18 years"],
    correct: "15 years",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Syrup and Water are mixed in 2:1 ratio to form 60 litres of a mixture. How much water needs to be added to make the ratio 1:2?",
    answers: ["60 litres", "85 litres", "55 litres", "Cannot be determined"],
    correct: "85 litres",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Felix and Adam win Rs 1210 together. 4/15 of Felix's share is same as 2/5 of Adam's share. How much did Adam win?",
    answers: ["Rs 484", "Rs 330", "Rs 360", "Data inadequate"],
    correct: "Rs 484",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Mary's salary is reduced by 10%. By what percentage must her new salary be increased in order to gain her old salary?",
    answers: ["137 %", "194 %", "100/9 %", "110 %"],
    correct: "100/9 %",
  },
  {
    question:
      "John earns 33.33% more than Peter. By what percentage is Peter's earning less than that of John's?",
    answers: ["22 %", "25 %", "26 %", "23 %"],
    correct: "25 %",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The price of sugar is decreased by 10%. As a consequence, monthly sales is increased by 30%. Find out the percentage increase in monthly revenue.",
    answers: ["17 %", "19 %", "18 %", "None of these"],
    correct: "17 %",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Jack consumes 75% of his salary. Later his salary is increased by 20% and he increases his expenditures by 10%. Find the percentage increase in his savings.",
    answers: ["51%", "60%", "50%", "55%"],
    correct: "50%",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Mary buys an item at Rs 25 in a sale and saves Rs 5. Find out the percentage of her savings.",
    answers: ["40/3 %", "55/3 %", "50/3 %", "None of these"],
    correct: "50/3 %",
  },
];
